<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Earl of Pembroke's case, in reference to the amendments in Wales.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1695</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 13 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B08975</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing E77[plus]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R232759</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">69648636</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 69648636</idno>
            <idno type="VID">184903</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B08975)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 184903)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2879:11)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The Earl of Pembroke's case, in reference to the amendments in Wales.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1695?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Place and date of publication suggested by Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Trinity College (Dublin, Ireland). Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Pembroke, Philip Herbert, --  Earl of, 1653-1683 --  Trials, litigation, etc.</term>
               <term>Decedents' estates --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-06</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-06</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:184903:1"/>
            <head>THE Earl of PEMBROKE's Caſe, In Reference to the Amendments in <hi>Wales.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <hi>PHilip</hi> late Earl of <hi>Pembroke,</hi> the Brother of the now Earl, having married the Dutcheſs of <hi>Portſmouth</hi>'s Siſter, in purſuance of an Agreement made by him, in Order to that Marriage, for ſettling a Jointure on her, in caſe ſhe ſurvived him, did by Demiſe and Redemiſe ſettle the yearly Rent of 1500 <hi>l. per annum,</hi> iſſuing out of all his Mannors and Lands in <hi>Glamorganſhire;</hi> and in order to make that a good Security to her, he having only in thoſe Mannors and Lands an Eſtate tail-male, with a Remainder in tail-male to the now Earl, did in the Year 1675, levy a Fine, and ſuffer two Recoveries of all the ſaid Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors and Lands, but declared no Uſe of the Freehold and Inheritance thereof, there being no Agreement for ſettling of any Eſtate on any Iſſue, Male or Female, on that Marriage. After the ſuffering of which ſaid Recoveries, the ſaid Earl <hi>Philip</hi> died without Iſſue-Male of his Body, having only one Daughter, the Lady <hi>Charlott Herbert,</hi> now Wife to the Lord <hi>Jefferye;</hi> after whoſe Death the now Earl of <hi>Pembroke</hi> being in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed that there were ſeveral groſs Errors in the ſaid Fine and Recoveries, did bring ſeveral Writs of Error to reverſe them, but could procure no Return to be made on the ſaid Writs of Error, till after the late Lord Chancellor <hi>Jefferye</hi> had concluded the ſaid Marriage of his Son; and two Perſons were ſent down by the ſaid late Lord Chancellor to procure Amendments to be made in the ſaid Fine and Recoveries; and then the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cords and Writs were returned in the Court of <hi>King's-Bench,</hi> as they were amended; ſome of which Amend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments being illegal, and not warranted by Law, and being procured by Power and Practice, the Effect of the ſaid now Earl's Bill is to ſet aſide the ſaid Amendments.</p>
            <p>The Amendments that the now Earl i<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ſiſts on to be made contrary to Law, is in altering of the Date of the Writ of Covenant, which was dated the <hi>1ſt</hi> of <hi>April,</hi> in 27 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. which was altered and dated the <hi>3d</hi> of <hi>November</hi> before, which they did to make it precede the <hi>Dedimus,</hi> for taking that Fine which was dated that <hi>5th</hi> of <hi>November;</hi> which being an Amendment of an Original Writ, is not warranted by the Common Law, or any Statute, and was ſo declared by the Judges, whilſt this Bill was depending in the Houſe of Peers; and that the Judg of the Grand Seſſions could not by Law make any ſuch Amendment.</p>
            <p>The other Error inſiſted upon by the ſaid Earl, is, That Earl <hi>Philip</hi> being not in Perſon in <hi>Wales</hi> at the time of ſuffering the Recovery, a Commiſſion, ſtiled a <hi>Dedimus,</hi> iſſued to ſeveral Commiſſioners named in that Commiſſion, impowering three or two of them to take the Earl's, naming his Attorney to appear for him, as Vouchee in the ſaid Recovery, which was executed by <hi>Herbert Salladin,</hi> and <hi>Francis Negus;</hi> where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>as <hi>Herbert Salladin</hi> was no Commiſſioner named in that Commiſſion, and ſo was executed but by one of the Commiſſioners therein named, and therefore void. To ſupply which groſs Error, the Judg of the Grand Seſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons ordered a new <hi>Dedimus</hi> to be made, and put <hi>Herbert Salladin</hi>'s Name into it, on pretence that the former <hi>Dedimus</hi> was loſt; and that <hi>Herbert Salladin</hi> was therein named one of the Commiſſioners for taking the ſaid Warrant of Attorney; which Pretence none of the Lord <hi>Jefferye</hi>'s Witneſſes, being examined at the Lords Bar, could make out or prove that <hi>Herbert Salladin</hi>'s Name was ever in ſuch Commiſſion.</p>
            <p>And the now Earl inſiſts on it, that his Name was not in any ſuch Commiſſion for theſe Reaſons:</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Firſt;</hi> That in the Entry of the ſaid Commiſſion on the Roll on Record, neither the Chriſtian Name nor Sirname of <hi>Herbert Salladin</hi> is mentioned.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Secondly;</hi> That the Name of <hi>Herbert Salladin</hi> in the Commiſſion for taking the Fine, is written on a Ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zure; and 'tis very probable it was ſo put into that Commiſſion after the Sealing of it; the Lord <hi>Jefferye</hi>'s Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs who made out the Commiſſion, being examined to that Matter at the Bar of the Lords, ſaid, he could not tell that it was put in before the Sealing thereof.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Thirdly;</hi> That when the now Earl ſent for Copies of the Records and Proceedings, in order to bring his Writs of Error, Mr. <hi>Hughes,</hi> the Officer who kept the Records in the Grand Seſſions, did in examining the Copies of the Records, after they were writ, refuſe the now Earl's Agent to peruſe the <hi>Dedimus,</hi> and did read to him the <hi>Dedimus</hi> for taking the Fine, inſtead of the <hi>Dedimus</hi> for taking the Warrant of Attorney for the Recovery.</p>
            <p>That the Deputy <hi>Prothonory,</hi> who had the Cuſtody of the ſaid Records being then Agent for the Lady <hi>Pembroke,</hi> did in the Year 1688, before the ſaid Amendments were made, offer one <hi>Anthony Phillpott</hi> one hundred Guinea's, if he would acknowledg he had ſeen the ſaid <hi>Dedimus</hi> for taking the ſaid Warrant of At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torney, and that the Name <hi>Herbert Salladin</hi> was therein written as a Commiſſioner.</p>
            <p>All which the now Earl thinks are plain Proofs that <hi>Herbert Salladin</hi> was never therein named a Commiſſioner; and that the Commiſſion is purpoſely imbezzl'd and conceal'd, that the Truth might not appear; that there might be a Pretence for making a new one under Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour that the former Commiſſion was right and caſually loſt.</p>
            <p>In the ingroſſed Bill there is a Proviſo to make the ſaid Mannors and Lands, in caſe the ſaid Fine and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coveries ſhould be revers'd, liable to ſuch Debts of the ſaid Earl <hi>Phillip,</hi> as the ſaid Mannors and Lands would have been ſubject unto, if the ſaid Fine and Recoveries had ſtood good, and not been revers'd. And alſo that in caſe the other Mannors and Lands deſcended and come to the Lady <hi>Charlotte,</hi> Wife of the now Lord <hi>Jefferyes,</hi> ſhould not be of the Value of 10000 <hi>l.</hi> to be ſold, being her Mother's Portion, to make thoſe Mannors and Lands, of which the ſaid Fine and Recoveries were levied and ſuffered, liable to the raiſing of ſuch Part of the 10000 <hi>l.</hi> as the ſaid other Mannors and Lands ſhall not amount unto.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="docket_title">
            <pb facs="tcp:184903:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>THE CASE OF THE Earl of <hi>Pembroke.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb facs="tcp:184903:2"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
